Hello everyone, this is Morisaki Wynn for Enjoy Simple English.
毎週月曜日はオリジナルのショートストーリーズ。
今日はDIY stairs 手作り階段。
母親が小学生の息子のためにお尻をベッドに作り替えようと奮闘する話です。
うまくいくのでしょうか?早速聞いてみましょう。
ママ、何をしてるの?
DIY
DIYは何ですか?
DIYは、自分でやることです
小学校にいるのに、あなたは大きく成長しています
私たちは、あなたの部屋に変更する必要があると考えています
私に変更するの?
イエーイ!
あなたはどうするの?
私たちは、あなたのフトンクローゼットの上半をベッドにしてあげることを考えています
Bed? Really?
Yes, then you'll have space for a desk so you can study
Wow, I'm going to have my own bed
Bed, bed, bed, bed
I'm happy to see you so happy
Now, let me get back to planning
I want to help
Oh, thank you
What should I do?
Hmm
First, I'm going to make stairs for you to climb up to the bed.
So, can you cut the wood?
I don't need stairs. It's not too high, so I can jump up.
I know you can.
But how about when you want to go to the bathroom in the middle of the night?
And I'm planning to use the space under the stairs to put things away.
ステアーとミニクローゼットになるんだ
いい考えだ
OK 木を切るよ
鎖を持ってくる?
早くしないよ
まずは全てを測ってみよう
テープを使ってクローゼットの床の高さを測ってみよう
84センチメートル
OK, then one stair is...
10 centimeters.
That's not enough, Yuta.
We will have to make more than eight steps.
And it's not enough space for each step to be a closet.
I see.
Then how high should they be?
Why don't we measure the steps in our house?
Can you go and measure the stairs?
Sure, Mom.
1ステップは20センチメートルです、ママ。
いいえ。
だから、
私は木を切り始めたい。
ちょっと待って、ユータ。
私が計算します。
では、
階段は84センチメートル高いでしょう。
もし、1ステップは20センチメートル高いなら、
階段は4センチメートル低いでしょう。
ああ、
だから、1つのステップは21センチメートルだよ。
4つのステップを作るよ。
分かった。21センチメートルだよね?
はい、そして、ない。
どのくらいの木材が厚いのか考えなきゃいけないよ。
はあ?
家に来たよ!
お、お父さんが仕事に戻ったよ。
何してるの?
ママが私に床を作るよ。
そう we are first going to make stairs but there's so much we have to
measure and think about we're getting nowhere
well why don't you go to a diy store they sell them really but do they sell
stairs that can be used as a closet sure i just saw an ad on the internet they
are on sale right now dad you are awesome
Why didn't I look on the internet first?
まさにドラえもん
押入れで寝てる方って結構いるみたいですよ皆さん
家具とか買うときに測ったりするじゃないですか
DIYももちろんそうだと思うんですけど
メジャー測ったりとかして
その時の数値とかをベースにして組み立てたりするんですけれども
その数値の表記として
Heightってのは高さ
Widthってのは幅
Depthってのが奥行きです
それではSee you tomorrow